good morning nosh on how guten morgen
- the air boys are my double let's
meditate okay okay okay thank you
yeah good clear your throat turn off
your phone
[Music]
please relax your fingers
pull in your stomach just a little bit
relax your mouth relax your admins try
to release all the tension in your
forehead and your heads
bring your chest out just a moment
little bit smile
and then please come to your breath
today let's just focus on long exhales
rather than counting just on relaxing
exhales
then please ask a root teacher hard
teacher to come and sit with you and it
should be very personal and pleasant
Pleasant they are I think rather than
trying to feel some sort of official
respect for them maybe just try to reach
a feeling of affection mutual affection
like old friends you've been to many
things with your heart teacher good
times bad times and they're just like a
old pair of jeans now comfortable
and there's a nice fragrance from them
like summer day or something because
and in your mind just praise them for
something beautiful about how they act
or how they treat people
and offer them a small gift I think it
would be nice to offer a single simple
good thought that you had yesterday
during the whole day just a small but
sincere good thought you had maybe about
somebody else
then open up and be honest about
something you've done recently that
wasn't very nice some small thing
then ask a teacher to teach you
perhaps through the people who are here
during this retreat please teach me
through that words and actions of the
people around me for this week
and please stay with me don't leave and
not just like this laughs but my teacher
nice wherever I go after this
I'd like you to think about the
activities you did last week at work and
at home you had certain jobs to do at
work you're supposed to finish certain
things you have to accomplish certain
things think about some of them and at
home you have jobs to do around the
house or apartment we do family just
think about two or three of those what
you did last week
I think for myself for example I was
working in my garden a lot because it's
time of year to do a lot of work in the
garden
everything's just waking up at work as
usual I was trying to do fundraising get
support for projects so for me I can say
Oh last week I I was trying to make my
garden beautiful and I was trying to
make sure that we had enough funds to do
different projects
didn't think about that steps you took
to get what you wanted in my case I
ordered some special fertilizer on
Amazon and I pulled out weed around the
house outside and I tried to write a
contract or an agreement
do you help fund some of our projects
then China think whether those actions
worked did they work in my case did the
garden respond did more beautiful
flowers come does it look like the
sponsors will help did the action to
work that you took last week
then you can please ask your teacher to
come to your heart you know what to do
do it slowly
ask them to stay inside of you and
influence your thoughts and words
actions today
and come to your bread three long
exhales don't open your eyes yet don't
move yet
okay now you can open your biggest judge
so we just did
meditation number eight page four and a
lot of the meditations are following the
refuge of Alice so we'll be talking
about the refuge house during the Lamia
in this lemon and what you'll find that
the point of this meditation is are you
taking refuge during your normal life
every day and a way to judge that the
temperature a way to a ruler for judging
that is how do you think things work you
see and I don't know the English word
work is very interesting you know like
oh this Aspen doesn't work or you know
this this fertilizer doesn't work or
this medicine doesn't work right and we
say work and really I think it's the
most valuable thing you can learn in
these classes in this all these long
room retreats 25 retreats the most
valuable thing maybe you can learn it's
about how things work because life is
about trying to make things happen
your whole life is spent trying to get
what you want trying to make things
happen you want your partner to be sweet
you want your garden to grow beautiful
you want your work to be successful and
and you always have a choice you can
take refuge or you can use self-existent
matches okay you can you can marry the
first husband who doesn't exist you
could spend your whole life trying to
make things happen
mechanically and and not through taking
refuge you see so really maybe this
meditation is the most important one so
in my example but he's from Valhalla who
lives in Costa Rica where you know
Dominican yes he sent me two bags of
special fertilizer called biochar he
works for this company or something and
then I put it on my roses and they they
like double in like one month it was
weird supernatural and they got all nice
and healthy and deep red leaves and you
know and so my human reaction is to go
on Amazon and I bought six bags more
there was a lot of money I said are bad
to rob because he has a garden I thought
him he knows why Ford appreciated by the
way there's one person in the room who
guided Diamond Mountain through some
very hard times and helped us grow for
many years and is still keeping all the
accounts perfectly and honest me and
keeps us legal and I'd like to give Rob
a head
so I put the stuff all over my garden
and everything exploded you know
everything's growing beautiful flowers
and um some of them are called
volunteers you know the volunteers it's
where their plants flower them they
plant themselves around your garden and
their volunteers are going crazy and so
then because I'm a human being in the
design room
samsara I buy more biochar fertilizer
you see but where did the beauty really
come from patience okay around me trying
hard not to get angry so really if I was
taking refuge if I understood taking
refuge to make my garden grow better I
would think of all the people who
irritate me and try to feel more patient
towards them and then just then by the
biochar you see it still okay to buy the
fertilizer but whether it works or not
depends on taking recipes okay so people
who have Gardens you know it's it's like
unpredictable you plant stuff you water
it properly you fertilize it properly it
grows and then some raccoon eats
you know why does that happen you get
everything right
mechanically right but you didn't make
the Karma
you didn't plant the seeds you see so
this meditation is maybe the most
important one and it's called don't try
other things you see it's how what
percent of what you did last week was
done with a knowledge of Refuge or or
what percent was done with the old
viewpoint okay what's the old viewpoint
if I put enough fertilizer on it me and
Mike were discussing what to spray on
the leaves of hollyhocks they get this
yellow does you get this yellow fungus
on them right so we're like he's using
the I'm using neem oil from India he's
using he's using jalapeno juice or some
and and then suddenly on your life you
know doesn't matter just think of
someone that you're not so happy about
and try to reconcile with them and then
fungus will go away right maybe you
don't have to put anything on it you
said I mean so I say number eight
meditation number eight which is part of
the first refuge Val what's the first
refuge now yeah don't take worldly
Rush's okay once you've taken refuge in
the Buddha jewel don't take worldly
refuge and it doesn't really mean you
can't respect Christian God or something
like that it doesn't mean things like
that it doesn't mean things like that it
means do you trust the biochar
fertilizer or do you trust your patients
you swim in them
okay and we'll talk more about that
later
you know but it's a fundamental mistake
that causes the wheel of life it's the
first wing if he is to trust the
fertilizer you see that's the blind man
I used to trust the fertilizer and for
my projects right I was like sweating
over some part of a contract you know
like how do I make this work you know
and then suddenly I had this
extraordinary break here you know
something weird happen like supernatural
and then ask we can also stupid to worry
about it you know what made it happen
was sharing Dharma you see I mean the
seeds from sharing dimer created some
ancient texts that saved my ass in the
project right UN say master Yin Yin say
when and it's like that okay so the
three days if you're going to meditate
for three days if it's me I will work on
meditation number eight a lot okay
like where are things really coming from
you know how can I get the things I want
you know I want my husband to act a
certain way you know I want my kids to
act a certain way
I want my projects to succeed I want my
garden to be beautiful you know and and
so the DC I thing the four steps right
there's a joke of DC I we could either
paid two thousand three hundred dollars
and come to the DCI teacher training in
June June
or if you want to you can just learn to
do this with your hand and then your dpi
teacher somebody says gee Michael you
know I don't know how to do this my
problem with my husband I know I had
this health problem over here
we're over here planting food that's a
bummer
I guess I right you are I'm somebody
else who wants to help them get it do do
meditation before you sleep to make
those seeds grow faster and so that's
taking refuge that equals taking refuge
what is thinking recipes for skies okay
it's just the fourth guest and two of
the outages are people and one of them
is it's an idea okay got it
the first one is a person you go to
Buddha you respect Buddha you make
offerings be thankful say thank you to
Buddha gratitude right I don't like this
offerings I don't like the word offering
so much I think it should be like just
thank-you notes
you know like flowers that are thank you
that's the whole purpose are offering is
or you gave me something thank you you
know that's the first kind of taking
refuges it's basically just show your
gratitude to Buddha thank you
okay make put a flower on the altar okay
the third one is is what we talked about
illicit vapor fine wise friends and hang
around them okay
that's Sangha you know surround yourself
with wise people good people okay
who understands seeds you know like I
was with what's in me Katie's mom Janice
you know and you know we were trying to
figure out I forget word fundraising
game you know and she's like in the
middle of this long complicated
conversation she says oh well why don't
we just help someone else with their
fundraising I'm like no no I know no we
gotta get on it and then everybody you
know surround yourself with people who
think that way who will correct you you
know who will correct guessing my car so
I guess now that's not kind of
necessarily work you you should help
someone else raise money you know that
means something like that
okay that's Sangha so first and third
are our people but the second one is
idea is an idea Dharma is a mindset
worldview right it's to approach things
understanding that you make things
happen by by making them happen for
other people okay got it
so really meditation aid is an
examination during your three days of
silence of your own life and see you
know ready to put your trust where do
you put your hope the decimation of the
textbook definition of refuges you know
what sort of us it means very rare word
and it means put all your hopes in
something put all your trust in
something the do you put all your trust
in biochar fertilizers or a destroyer
Justin
or in situations that you rotate you how
do you make your flowers grow around
your house okay and so that's that's
probably the most important meditation
and it's the best way to spend your
three days okay examine your life see
what you're up to
what are you what are you trying to
achieve in your life and are you taking
message which means are you using the
force Destin I'm okay and it's I don't
know why but personally I have a
resistance to it it's easier to buy
fertilizer yeah I know but what are we
gonna do you know I don't know why I
don't want to surrender to this idea
I just want to order something I'm
Amazon so anyway
okay meditation number nine
so I before your three-day retreat I'm
going to spend a lot of time on the
meditations because you have to do them
okay and then we'll cover the same
points in the book so I like to I like
it when the book says the same thing I
said in some complicated Tibetan
sentence and you have faith in it okay I
hope okay number nine meditation um nine
which we we don't have to meditate on
you can do it yourself but there's a
famous story in the long room which we
will need together and the abbot of the
monastery in in in my monastery when
where all the monks are together it's
three thousand months huge
sergej cermet both men in front there
will be this Abbot you know this big guy
very wise and very you have a lot of
power
there's no checks and balances since the
in the muster what the abbot says
happens you know and and there's some
pretty severe punishments can be given
and things like that you know so people
respect and people didn't fear of damage
[Music]
and the China influency of it and so
there's a story that two marks were
sitting together and one of them had the
ability to read people's minds and the
abbot was leading a very major ceremony
you know like at our ceremony or
something and the one month is going
like we're on your own you know and then
he takes in a monk next time he says you
end up dumb funny his legs of our Abbot
sitting up there yeah he's not a brute
what are you talking about you know you
say something like that you're gonna do
it you know don't think things like that
you know it's just no no he's not a
Buddhist why he never took lessons he's
like he's a biochar fertilizer okay that
was a very famous conversation you know
all the abbot believed in mechanical
themes and not in seeds you see the
abbot tries to make more money by
working harder or buying more things or
selling more things or doing more
advertising you know the abbot doesn't
understand that the way to make more
money is to help someone else new money
you see so the average not taking refuge
in that worldview
so the abbot is not a Buddhist okay and
and we talked about the opposite what's
that what's the opposite of that
yeah you can teach a group of a thousand
business people and I have rednecks from
Florida architect conference one
thousand architects hospital architects
okay redneck in English means that into
that they call grim brain but it's the
same thing
lab a jungle it means that very
conservatives like they don't want to
help any foreign countries or you know
they don't want to they just want
America to be strong and they don't want
to help anybody and and they asked me to
give a talk and at that time in the
American Congress there was a vote to
sell an oil company to China or not you
know and you know of course they are
very redneck conservative so they all
said I asked him at the beginning of the
talk and and it was really like a
football stadium because each one wanted
his own desk most like that I couldn't
see the people at that back it was too
far away and they had this big desk you
know and so I asked them do you think
America should sell this oil come to
Decatur and there are no no no then I
taught them slowly the pan and the four
stabs very slowly I didn't say anything
about oil companies and we I talked for
like two hours and then finally at the
end I said so let's talk about energy
supplies for America how can we
guarantee energy supplies for America
tonight
number one energy supplies for America
be strong America what's number two
yeah just find another country they made
much number three help them get that
fellas needs to die and then be happy
about it and then suddenly they all
started like smiling and crying you know
like oh that's so nice that's so
beautiful
that's so that feels so good that feels
so correct they came up all these people
came out they're like give me five man
engagement oh yeah what shallow company
you know and in that moment that 1,000
redneck architects became brief because
they took lessons got it it's so the
opposite is true
sometimes the Billiton are buddhist and
sometimes and non-buddhist our duty got
it that's meditation number nine okay so
you have to think about you know I think
most of us are Buddhist about twenty
percent of the time you know we make our
guarded beautiful by being patient about
twenty ten percent of the time and in -
is another time we're digging and
pulling weeds and putting fertilizer
things like that okay all right do you
have to if the plaintiff is do you still
have to dig the weeds and put the
fertilizer mostly and later you can do
miracles we'll talk about it but you
still have to take the aspirin okay
whether it works or not is is how much
you help someone else okay
so you see where DCI is tying in to
mommy and it's always going to be that
way nothing in DC I didn't come from for
the scriptures and and in the different
manuals in the bath where nobody reads
it is where everything came from okay
all right
I want to talk about meditation number
ten okay
we have to do twenty-seven before you
start your retreat meditation number ten
is called Earth the foundation and the
inner essence refuge and commitment
keeping the refuge vows which we will
cover but the first one is what I just
said okay really the first refuge now is
make your garden grow by patience and
not by biochars fertilizer okay or maybe
both okay that viewpoint or that
worldview that taking refuge is required
for all further Buddhist practices by
tradition okay you have to take refuge
before you can take Bodhisattva vows
before you can take laymen's vows before
you can take novice vows before you can
take medium nun vows before you can take
full nun vows or a full monks vows the
eight vows right trotting moksha they
all depend on on reference vows if you
don't take refuge values you can't take
the rest okay so in the scriptures
taking refuge the simple vows is
considered like the earth and then all
the trees all the flowers everything
that grows out of the earth comes from
that and then kabocha routine makes a
big deal about
you know I was I planted iris balls okay
and they grow into in my house they grow
into colors okay a pale yellow and a
pale purple very beautiful very stunning
I'll show you a photo later I just had
to take a photo of them they're so
beautiful and the dirt where I live is
90% rocks it's just like Ireland right
mr. donor if I take the rocks out of a
few square feet and the ground drops
like six inches you know and it's
terrible and the ground is hopeless
it takes about three hours to plant a
rose because to dig a little holes just
to pull out all the rocks is impossible
you know then I plant these bulbs then
the iris grows and this colors come out
and I'm looking at the color something
how how did that come out of my rocks
you know how did the plant
suck the light chemicals out of the
rocks to make these colors like it's
it's it's like weird you know there's no
yellow or purple in the dirt
it's terrible color it's like brown
black and dirt dust and then somehow
this stupid bulb sucks out only the
yellow from the ground only the purple
and then puts it all into the flower but
only in the flower not in the plan it's
weird it just seems weird to me okay my
bunker says we're actually just the same
okay you take good refuge you understand
taking refuge then all the other
Buddhist practice produces beautiful
colors got it like everything your tent
practice you know deep mystical things
deep meditation you know difficult
practices they all come from refuge
refugees that chemical that makes the
yellow flower okay it's in the earth so
it's the foundation so that's why I put
you know it's the same as fruits I put
an apple tree here in the picture and
whether the rest of your Buddhist
practice is successful intense on
whether you take refuge well it's the
soil I call it dirt and then V says no
no its soil cat used to tell me that
don't call it dirt thank you Michael so
you do the same thing okay so it's the
foundation okay refugees are foundation
so during that meditation when you do it
you can think of all your practice your
meditation practice your yoga practice
your study and you can try to tie it in
to your refuge you know if your refuge
is good your yoga will be good your
meditation will be good and your study
will be good and your service of other
people will be good and if you're
refugees if your message is not to talk
if the earth is weak it won't be good I
have to tell you bad news about my poop
tree bird poop tree do you know about my
bird poop tree okay I got to tell you
about the bird poetry the DCI people
know people ask me why do why do creepy
like why do gangster drug lords become
rich okay why do mafia guys become rich
if karma is correct they shouldn't get
rich but they do some of them
so then I said that's called bird poop
and I said what bird poop and I said
well there's a tree that comes from
China it's called mulberry and we need
it because silkworms
only eat mulberry leaves so to make silk
you need silkworms
to make silkworms you gotta have
mulberry leaves that's the only thing
they like to eat they're more picky than
me okay and somebody brought it to
Arizona for many years it was secret
in ancient China if it was a death
penalty if you told someone about
mulberry trees and the first mulberry
seeds were carried out of China in the
Hat of a noblewoman who wanted to share
them and she hid them in her hat in any
way they grow all over Arizona they grew
in my school when I was a little kid and
we used to climb them and they're nice
because they don't need much water and
the birds like them because they make a
little berry mulberry purple berry so
anyway I always wanted a mulberry tree
but my gardener partner said I don't
like mulberry trees they make mess on
the ground you know then one day I went
out I was working in the garden and and
there was a plant about this high you
know and I'm like I asked my party I
said what is that and she said oh oh she
said oh my god that's a mulberry she
said did you plant that so no no I
didn't do anything I don't even know
what it is she said it must be a bird
poop mulberry tree because they eat the
mulberry and they're in a rush like
someone trying to get to meditation
class and they they don't digest this
the berries and they they poop the seats
and then the seeds have nice poop
fertilizer around them and they grow
pretty fast okay so I always
fighting about my good karma that a bird
pooped mulberry tree in my front yard
but then they said I don't want it in
the front yard that you have to move it
I'm like okay so I dug it up while I was
digging it up I I split the taproot
which is going to kill it
she said it can't grow now it will die I
said what can I plant anywhere in the
backyard okay you can plant it but it's
going to die then I planted it and it
grew it's about three meters high no and
but then the Gophers came and these are
little like rats and they live under the
ground and they eat the roots so now I
don't know so the bad news for my bird
poop tree friends I went out to work on
the tree and I touched it and it was
like there's no foundation you know
that's what your life is like if you
don't take refuge properly okay you grab
the tree and it goes just it just went
like this then I shake it and their
roots are gone all the roots are gone
this animal ate them so I asked her do I
have to pull it out she said she said
really you should point out I said can I
just try so you have to pray for my
mulberry tree okay I'm still going it's
still going it's trying to put a wreath
on what it means that you need a
foundation okay without without those
roots forget it everything else is fake
it looks strong and when you touch it it
goes boom you know you get a little
problem in your life and your practice
collapses you know because the woods
aren't good okay it's like it was really
disappointing
I I touched today when and as I told it
and went were
no I and you practice will be like that
if you don't know about refuse if you
don't take good recipes your practice
will be no foundation okay
and and you will collapse the first time
you have a problem okay and Wayne okay
your practice will be like that also
yoga stuff like that alright then what
time is it
[Music]
let's do one more meditation then take a
pee-pee break okay all right we'll do it
number 11 so get ready to meditate oh by
the way so that's how mafia guys get
rich they gave some money into their
nephew ten years ago they did one nice
thing then they killed 20 people but the
gift of a few some money to their nephew
made them rich and it will always go
away will always collapse okay alright
mafia guys well to spread cool seats
accident
so please come to your breath you can
check in with the llama in your heart
you don't have to do the fall
preliminaries every session you can do
it once in the morning and then in the
following sessions on the same day you
can just check in with your llama
sitting in a grain of crisps a grain of
sugar in your heart like a clear crystal
globe
and bring your mind to the center to
your breath let go of the outside world
like all the things happening everywhere
in your life these three days are your
days let go of all the other things
you're doing and you will find that you
do them better afterwards come to your
breath
then I'd like you to think about some
pretty serious mistakes you've made in
your life maybe before you knew about
Karma
and those are kind of like time bombs
there
those seeds didn't come back to us yet
many of them and some of those actions
were pretty serious you know I was
involved in an abortion I can think of
that kind of when I was in college so I
can think of time bombs waiting for me
you know some very heavy negative
Karma's are waiting inside of me and at
some point they will blow up and I now
get some very serious problems
[Music]
so this meditation is the first part is
a little bit difficult we have to try to
think of people that we really hurt
mistakes like that that we made mostly
done so we'll take a few minutes china
think of one or two grand mistakes
you've made in your life
didn't think about the few things you're
doing nowadays where you are taking good
refuge you are using the four steps you
are trying to make things happen by
helping other people it doesn't have to
be a big thing maybe you are helping a
friend with a relationship problem or
maybe you're helping someone financially
but you are taking baby steps to deal
with problems than to reach goals by
serving someone else so think of two or
three things you're doing which are
using seeds which are serving others to
meet your goals and that's taking refuge
think of that time so you're taking
refuge
and
the third and last part of this
meditation is to just spend a few
minutes appreciating about the baby
steps you are taking to solve problems
or reach goals by serving others
planting seeds actually damage the old
godsey's so understanding where things
come from reaching goals by planting
seeds by serving other people helping
them reach their goals the power of
those babies deaths is small baby steps
it's very very powerful and non-rem says
it will block or destroy even very old
powerful bad seeds so try to draw a
mental connection between the small good
things you're doing now with
understanding seeds taking refuge and
draw a line in your mind back to those
big mistakes you made many years ago in
my case 45 years ago and appreciate that
that new way of life is damaging and
disabling the old bad seeds and you are
again you are protecting yourself from
those time bombs
drive that line and you might make that
connection
and
then watch 3d 3dd exhales don't move
here don't open your eyes here check in
with your lover in your heart and then
open your eyes take a stretch so the
picture which you can memorize right
just memorize the pictures and then you
can figure out what they're supposed to
be about okay what's the picture yes oh
sorry he has it up there yeah like he's
protecting himself from time bombs that
he'd laid ten years ago five years ago
okay he's he's got an umbrella okay so
that's why we put the lady with the
umbrella on your schedule for example
okay so you are protecting yourself not
only from future problems but you can
protect yourself from possible bad seeds
that you planted okay
refuge has this beautiful ability we
talked about it in The Wheel of Life the
second link of the wheel is what's the
picture yeah a guy making partner and by
the way I was reading an interesting
comment I think bus abundant he said the
fact that it's a wheel is important that
the Potter is using a wheel yeah but
those are seeds that you haven't put in
the ground yet then they're not they
might not grow if they never get the
necessary water and fertilizer okay then
link number 10 there's two links in the
of the twelve which are karma what's
link number ten pregnant woman's okay it
means the food is ready to open okay
and then there's a lot of discussion of
what causes what takes the seeds from
number two to number ten what is it why
didn't they just make one link in the
wheel which was coming why do they have
to because the first one is karma that's
actually it's planted but it hasn't
ripened and intended has ripened and the
babies coming out going to come out okay
so something happens also underground
right it's kind of a miracle it's very I
don't know exciting when you're a
gardener you plant some watermelon seeds
you cover them you put water you give it
biochar fertilizer and they do something
happens down there my little guys are
running around in the seed line the
water wakes them up you know and they're
like oh we gotta get this thing going
like some miracle happens when the water
touches the seed which it never does
right and you know something triggers
back something triggers the seed
okay and it's not understanding seed
that takes the seed from two to ten
linked to that Ming ten so if you
understand these and you use them it
damages your old Betsy's got in they
don't get the energy which takes them
from just planted to ready to open they
never get that water or the nutrients
that wake up the little guys in the
seeds got it so just the habit of
getting things in your life by helping
others to get them destroys the power of
your open sea sea so you kill two birds
with one stone bad example
you know your you plant good seeds for
your success but by doing that by
understanding seeds you destroy the old
ones or you deactivate them okay got it
so when you take refuge you're
protecting yourself from old mistakes
you made and you don't have to worry
about them they will never open they are
planted but they will never open
somebody said I don't like running
around with a billion bad seeds in my
head guess you thought that I'm never
going to open I said well they don't
take out my space
they say on the tip of a needle you can
put a billion seeds so okay no problem
this is the kind of some plants will
love if something invades them they will
grow a cyst around the siblings like a
hard coating around the problem and then
the plant will grow fine you see I mean
so what you're doing you're putting
those bad seeds you're coating them with
like steel or something and they will
never grow they will sit there forever
frustrated that they couldn't grow you
know and you will never get the problem
you're supposed to have okay got it
that's that's a cool meditation if
you're working nowadays on obstacles if
you're having obstacles to relationship
or your finances or your health do
number eleven okay work on number 11 got
it all right okay we'll start
okay that side is okay I like it when
you make noise because it means you're
having fun so don't worry or else you're
yelling at each other I don't know we're
going to do one more meditation okay you
ready
you can hear my stomach making noise I
[Music]
recorded with Amazon I recorded some of
myself and they you go to a special room
it's on Springs and there's a window and
the guy sits with the book and you sit
with the book and he stares at you and
if you say the slightest thing wrong he
says stop start again and then this guy
came in with a big teller a lady
actually and she she says I'm ready for
you and I'm like what
and she tied it on my stomach and she
said we always tie a pillow on your
stomach when you're recording it out of
audiobooks because your stomach makes
noise so if you put the iPhone here you
can get the full get you Michael
here we go relax your eyelids
relax your mouth
shoulders are maybe still a little bit
tight check check your shoulders
especially if you did work class
yesterday
just slightly tense your stomach
this meditation which is number 11 I
think in this one we do the opposite
from what we did last time so I'd like
you to go back in your life even very
far when you were a very young and what
other seeds that you are most proud of
when did you do the really kind things
for someone else took care of someone
who was very sick or served poor like
our New York Sun God doing what are the
moments when you really sacrifice what
you wanted and serve someone else take a
few minutes and think about the
highlights of your spiritual life
and
and again please think about small baby
steps you are taking in nowadays to
achieve your goals or solve your
problems by using seeds the four steps
to plant good seeds and the four powers
to stop old ones think about the
progress you're making the evolution in
this new view of what makes things work
yes
and then finally draw this connection
again and those good things you did many
of them were long before you really
understood about seeds though those old
good seeds are waiting in your mind to
grow and they are watered they are woken
up by all the attempts you make nowadays
to use the four steps to use seeds which
is taking refuge so try to appreciate
and draw a mental connection between the
attempts you are making nowadays to
plant seeds and the very huge old good
seeds that you planted which have been
multiplying ever since then and if you
can in your three-day retreat and in
your meditations if you can strengthen
that mental connection between your
practices nowadays as good seeds you
planted long ago that have been building
up lots of interest then it will trigger
those season and caused them to flower
in your life in the coming weeks and
months then you'll see a very sharp
increase in beautiful things in your
life so draw that connection
and then try to imagine how those seats
might open if you I don't know help
someone financially try to imagine how
your life will become very stable and
you'll have enough to do the things you
want to do to help other people and if
it was that you serve someone who is
elderly or sick you can look forward to
some very good health strong health for
many years and if it's that you help
someone with their relationship that you
can look forward to a very beautiful
relationship with your partner your
family friends because you triggered
them you ordered them by taking refuge
and using these principles of seeds and
refusing to do things that don't really
work
three deep exhales
then you can slowly up take a stretch
okay I'm going to do some good to know
Miriam
you
okay
I'll remind you where we left off
yesterday it's kind of technical I
apologize but when you get there you
appreciate it we're talking about the
first of the five paths which is called
passive accumulation of piling up good
comer okay solemn and it has three parts
called trimmer gang symbol lesser medium
and greater and those three parts
connect to different holiday suburb
buddha's eventually okay so there are
versions of qualities of buddha that you
master early on somebody asked me
yesterday
the four recollections right the four
awarenesses how come you're already
using the pen if you just started the
first part during the first path you you
are you are getting some teachings about
the pen but not the full thing okay
preliminary emptiness teachings okay and
then when we got to the greater part of
the first path i said i wasn't happy
with the i went and got you some stuff
to explain it and i didn't like it it
wasn't complete so this morning i got i
got it okay so I'll explain it to you
it's a little complicated and you'll see
why okay let me see
[Music]
they're the full name okay okay this is
complicated just don't worry about it
it's called the poet DJ Don debates with
turkey come bus okay po-wei DJ don't
damage your ticket come back okay it's a
long name I'll give you the meaning of
the name and then you'll see why I had
to look it up
Pawar means to give up something duty
means a factor or a cause or triggers
gemba means to possess surgery means
miracles conv means somebody's feet or
legs okay you ready
the miracle legs of those who possess
the factors which can eliminate okay it
doesn't mean anything okay so I went I
went and got a good explanation and I
looked through a million pages of
Scripture because we have a database and
that database is because of people like
John Brady Nicholas Shaw and Adam and
Joe day and I think you should thank
them
we were in India in Munster Barry giving
DCI talks and we had a guests with us
from Singapore and they came with us to
see the people working on the ancient
books and they got all excited
candy got excited and those people have
been working for 30 years this is the
31st year they are working some of them
have been working the whole time the
project is 31 years old and they never
had health insurance and so I'd like to
say Candy's taking care of that
so she's doing a lot of stuff like that
thank you for that
she just squeezes people and money comes
out I don't know how you have to teach
me okay
so I I don't feel comfortable if I don't
explain something which is in the book
okay I didn't want to do it he mentioned
it okay then I don't know if the Chinese
had a foot no nor I don't know to
explain the last three weeks for example
does it Stanley I don't think so it's
complicated
most people won't want to go there okay
[Music]
okay
that's unusual those are difficult okay
good all right so anyway here's about
the four miracle legs okay the word leg
means you're collecting karma which
supports the ability to do miracles okay
so we're going to see that again I think
this afternoon in Buddhism sometimes
you'll say this guy has good legs
it doesn't mean pretty it means good
foundation in morality or something
because they standing on strong
foundation they say good legs okay
sometimes they call Buddha the guy with
good legs okay or the lady with good
legs so so that's that why they call it
the four legs and they are kinds of
shell meter okay there are kinds of deep
meditation okay these four are kinds of
deep meditation and I'm going to give
you an explanation by
it just happens to be that the best
explanation in the million pages is from
the textbook writer from a monastery
called Jeremy I don't know why okay
first one is called the miracle leg of
aspiration okay
hoping to reach high goals okay and it's
a kind of one pointed mind meditation
deep meditation and its function is to
work against the five obstacles to
meditation arguably the first one you
give me the rest later
okay I don't feel like meditating today
I'll meditate tomorrow that's the first
obstacle to meditation what's the second
one no yes okay yeah
Jenga is called forgetting it means
losing the object it doesn't mean forget
okay it doesn't mean I can't remember
what my mama told me to meditate that it
doesn't mean that are you warm you want
to freeze okay so the word is to forget
the object but the meaning is you start
thinking about a hamburger when your
your llamas face in the meditation
slowly it changes into a Big Mac that's
the second one then one yeah
don't assume education together okay the
mind gets too high or the mind gets too
low number four
yeah you don't take action you you you
forget if your mind goes low you don't
think of something cool to bring your
mind up if your minds too high
you don't think of death which will
bring it down okay
what's then what's the fifth problem
taking action with you you know leave
leave it if it ain't broke don't fix it
if it's not broken don't fix it if the
meditations going smooth leave it alone
okay
don't keep checking okay so the first of
the form miracle legs is a meditation
where you're able to stop those five
problems okay okay
second one is a kind of one-pointed
meditation where you are extremely you
have extremely good effort you're able
to hang in there when things are tough
and you break through obstacles in your
meditation you you hang in there and you
work hard it's hard work in meditation
that's the miracle leg number two okay
miracle a number three it's called it's
called three different names in
Scripture I think only one of them is
correct simple which means to think okay
the definition of Karma assemble
somebody today you know mental Karma is
thinking okay so somebody means thinking
sin means my sandbox means thinking okay
so the third miracle leg is called
thinking but it has a specific meaning
and it means to build on your meditation
ability each time you meditate so based
on the success you had last year at
Diamond Mountain in your three daily
tree
you work again this year and you keep
building and your meditation gets better
better you keep coming back to Diamond
Mountain you know to see that mr. and
mrs. done and your meditation gets
stronger each time you come back that's
the meaning of number three it's called
it's called thinking but what it means
is building on what you on the
meditation you did before okay
and if you don't meditate regularly it
doesn't happen okay but if you do right
meditate regularly even though you may
have bad days it builds on each other
and a year later you're much better okay
okay the fourth one
it's called meditation where you are
correctly okay it's called meditation
where you act correctly out correctly
means you can think about the emptiness
of things correctly okay you start to
analyze things and that's that has eight
causes okay so when you explain the four
legs you have to talk about the five
problems we should expel already that
was in the first leg and when you get to
the fourth leg you have to talk about
the eight good things there are triggers
for giving up things okay so now we got
that that word was part of the name
right of the four they were called
miracle legs which help you to give up
which are triggers that help you to give
up negative things okay so it comes in
the fourth mark okay that's why I was
having trouble yesterday all right I
found a lazy author who just gave it
that long name and I didn't know what
the heck he's talking about okay now I
found a Sarah main Lama
he's from 1500 and we said so he says
you want to know the eight
okay he gives them a piece very thorough
you will recognize the first floor doing
but so what depe shinjang anybody
trigger anything for anybody doing but
so a gay bashing job those other four
antidotes to the first meditation
problem they're famous that's why
there's more added dose than problems in
the study of meditation if you took this
year level three you should notice right
eight antidotes five problems because
there's three actually antidotes for the
first one okay I like to call it the
high school girlfriend okay
in the discussion of the first
meditation problem and the four
antidotes to it I like to talk about the
high school girlfriend okay
why first one boomba and I can remember
this I can remember every day I had to
leave one class they the school decided
I could write the school Constitution
instead of going to class once one class
of day so I would go to the cafeteria
and write and then I'd always past this
classroom and there was a really pretty
girl inside you know and I just like run
into doors and stuff so I just thinking
you know I'd like to take her out or
something that's called Dumba that's the
first meditation correction what's the
first meditation problem yeah no it's
not really amazing this it's yeah it's
like it's like I don't feel like doing
it today I'll do it tomorrow you can say
the first meditation obstacle is I'll do
it tomorrow
for sure I'll do it tomorrow I'll start
my diet tomorrow
you know for sure I'll do yoga tomorrow
today I'm just a little tired
okay I just don't feel that good today
okay so that the first correction is to
want it you know I run it it's like the
girlfriend you know she's not the
girlfriend right yet she just looking
through the window you're like I want
that okay so think of that or a
boyfriend okay in high school I say I
want that that looks nice
okay what the ability to meditate well
that looks cool I would like that okay
it's like some kind of attraction okay
I want that okay that's number one then
so long so uh means move your ass do
something silver similar to cinder okay
do something in my case I did the
classic thing at Washington High School
in Arizona you hang out near her locker
and then when she's coming around the
corner you bump into her and drop her
books and then you know you pick up her
books and then you talk to her you
thought so sorry you know what's your
name are you busy on Friday actually if
it has them out of order I'm sorry I
have to change it okay goodbye
who has them out of order and the first
victim by witches I like it okay
the second one is damn part which is
safe which is you know I believe it will
help me okay I believe in it okay dipa
shredder what they call guru Jason
nephew shut up
it's a crotchless
okay Jivamukti suitable choices the
person in charge now
his name is corrupted from shredder so
the second one is damper which means you
see the good qualities in it
you're always counting her good
qualities okay so timber means you like
her waist totally out of order
I'm sorry Deborah means it would you
have you like it it's safe and you would
decide can we start again they forget
the tuition Joe he got them right away
out of order I'm sorry okay damp of
first Deborah means in meditation you
understand the good qualities of
meditation you have faith that this can
help me okay that's first I'm sorry
so cancel everything he's got the matter
order I apologize dampe is the first one
and that's where if somebody says what's
cool about her we can make a list okay
it's a what kind of meditation shadow
boom shadow oh you all know it's cool
she looks nice she's got a good car you
know okay you can make a list she had a
good car so those are the we can make a
list that's first okay sorry let's start
again
deeper and it's called face but it's not
really safe it's just I can tell you
five good things about meditation or I
can tell you five cool things about this
girl okay vampa Dumba means I would like
to take her out
I want that okay that's the second one
he's got him out of order there but
timber then to walk then drop her books
do something
okay move okay so what to get meditation
okay and then sim Jeung is what yeah it
seems young means you got good at it you
took her out three or four times you
know how to get her to kiss you you know
it's all everything's going good okay so
shim chung means you get good at it
cause you do it a few times okay you did
it enough times that you get good at it
it seems like divided into two what it
does Shin Jang is divided into two
physical and mental okay your body gets
used to meditation posture and your mind
gets used to military okay so those are
the first four of the eight got it you
know this for because you studied DCI
level three okay
and those are all going to overcome your
those four together fight Laila and that
and that's why there's eight antidotes
and only five problems because there's
three extra in the first one okay no
problem
okay then he says timber what's timber
regulation shishun no he's got it
reversed again I don't know why it's
doing that
the should go shaking first and in DUMBO
okay what station in meditation it's the
fire alarm
do we have silence it's the it's a thing
in your mind because okay when you're
meditating and suddenly you realize your
lamas face turned into hamburger you
know you're meditating on lunch you're
thinking about where you're going to
have some lunch and slowly without
noticing it your sweet llama face turned
into a hamburger and you've been
meditating on a hamburger for like three
minutes four minutes
and then part of your mind should go
beep beep and you're like what's wrong
we said did you look at what you're
meditating on oh oh it's a hamburger
yeah big Kemba comes in it pulls them
right back to the llama space okay it
says so good to hamburger for a while
pull the llama back that's
timba okay bring in the object back in
the mine
okay then you've got Samba and he
doesn't explain it somebody's paintings
probably it's continued thinking about
the object and then time you know means
attitude of equanimity about the object
you know you don't feel hatred and you
don't feel desire you enjoy it but you
don't we wouldn't hurt someone to get it
okay that's called equanimity okay okay
don't matter for miracle legs okay more
than you wanted to know but I like to be
thorough okay
and that's the only place you can get a
good explanation of it I didn't find
anything else in all the Tibetan
literature yeah last four and now you're
going to make me work recollection
watchfulness thinking and equanimity it
does eight together are the fourth leg
what tells me about he doesn't say
nobody says um you know if you're
interested we could go into the word
tummy oh there's three classic meanings
[Music]
just briefly although it's not the
subject today
it can mean equanimity between hatred
and desire it can mean Karma which is
mutual and it can mean a kind of
meditation okay all right okay here we
go
we're back to the scripture why didn't
we talk about all that we were talking
about the first pass why are we talking
about that we were talking about
somebody on the first track lowest
motivation lowest path minimum Buddhist
okay minimum Buddhist so according to
that idea what do you have to have to be
a Buddhist you have to be on the first
pass how do you get there you have a
personal disaster okay your mom has to
die in your arms you have to your
brother has to commit suicide something
like that
okay and I have a very interesting list
of all my close friends what was it that
got them to Buddhism and it's kind of
unbelievable yes okay okay yeah exactly
yeah and he's gonna expand on it and
tell you this is minimum Sangha but look
at all these other co-founders okay
they're good good point so now we know
where we are he's talking about Sangha
jewel minimum person what's the
motivation of a listener truck
yeah basically I just want to get to
their mother I don't really care about
the home world
I don't want to be unhappy okay dad
showed up top notch on the table but if
that person achieves our heart counting
the intensity they get much more cruel
qualities soap bubble Lord Shiva
dung they can take many outside objects
like I have here only five things to
drink this morning and located in our
heart can can't go like this and they
all become a little job in there Tom and
they can drink it and they get five
drinks okay they have this power to take
multiple outside objects and and turn it
into one tiny things okay like that step
are Sachin mainly I'm painting and dinky
grenade to kill Mahmoud tumba okay this
is another very very difficult subject I
don't like it because when I did my
progression exam quest somebody asked me
this question and I didn't know the
answer and it was very embarrassing so I
don't like this something but just for
you right I went and boned up on it so
there's called say punky tha stay safe
on tha the thing which triggers many
things to the end okay it's a Buddhist
concept okay the thing which triggers
many things to the end it's a Buddhist
concept there are ten different ones
[Music]
for example the four primary colors
which Adam can tell us easily because he
translated
yeah you know yeah whatever okay great
so the four primary colors are four of
them the four main elephants are four of
them thought you made them with that
earth ah-choo earth water fire wind okay
and then there's one called
Nam Kham space and I think there's
consciousness okay so these kids and
what it refers to is the ability to
change those things in an object okay
so like if I have power over the earth
element I can make this metal mountain
just with my meditations okay or I can
if I have say rocket engines in I can
turn water solid and I can walk across a
lake if I have that level of Prayer or
that level of concentration
so we believe what Jesus did is real
itself a contingent there's a word for
it
he turned their water element into Earth
and he walk across a bank okay or I saw
it in some other movie hidden chartered
Crouching Tiger here whenever somebody
runs across something okay we believe
it's real
we believe it's possible if you have a
high meditation you can adjust the
elements in an object okay or colors
which basically means you can make a
cell phone turn into a watermelon okay
jig me I need more watermelon for you
okay don't forget looking turn things
into other things okay that's now why is
it called to the end it means anything
okay but it's a very confusing word in
Buddhism okay so anyway it's a
meditation that allows you to emanate
objects you know you can make an
elephant appear in the room wheel you
can change water into solid you can run
across it like that okay you can climb
into the sky like that okay why is he
talking about all this he wants to show
how cool the Sun is how cool is it
summer
okay okay go Nate - good mobile you can
emanate anything you want
good job car your size checkbox so you
can travel through the sky to teach
students in different countries without
an airplane without United Airlines and
I mean I'm embarrassed to say my airline
isn't United but I already I already
started acting dinner it was pretty bad
into Dutch ambient in young talk to me
battle your day all these are are good
qualities of in our heart on the lower
track on the lowest chart listener child
okay I think shy footer was considered
in Lugano Dara considered lower our
pasta never good qualities inconceivable
them birthday Jay
after the Lord Buddha passed God will
taper till they shackled in English his
given name nanda who were gonna hear
from if you go to Indonesia so we have a
program August 2023 24th at a place
called Borobudur in Indonesia and it's
both basically it's a mountain that was
carved into a mandala a very high high
mountain and the whole mountain was
carved into Mandela and it has two and a
half thousand panels about the size of
this wall of the story of all the
Buddhist deeds in all the body starts
and speeds so we're going to go there
August 23rd 24th and I'm going to teach
some of the panels that relate to how
the Wheel of Life was first painted okay
so if you have time talk to Jenny okay
and you're welcome to come anyway that's
just one story of how the Wheel of Life
is painted and there are two other
stories and this monk named Nunda it was
involved in the second story okay and
the third story is about a very
beautiful lady who complained about the
lack of women's rights in Buddhism
[Music]
during the Buddhist time and that led to
the third painting of the Wheel of Life
so it's a beautiful story very powerful
story but you have to come to Indonesia
you don't get to hear ok gamma mu theta
due date so this after the Buddha passed
away Nunda defeated some other scholars
in debate ok and he taught for seven
days shotgun and he
got 80,000 people to see emptiness
directly okay in seven days of teaching
he got 80,000 people saw emptiness
directly okay and here's Louis Nava
our hug got it he's Louis novel on a
hunt so the saga must be pretty cool
that's the idea he wants to say about
that I like this story and I think we
have time to tell it no we don't we
could cut yoga shorter
so there was I believe you the Humana
name
oppa Gupta in Tibetan is called near day
okay but Gupta he was teaching now our
teacher the Lamia version and I'll teach
you the real story okay from the future
okay so here's a lot of in version and
just woke up he was teaching Dharma
dude dude dictation by the way big toes
a very weird word that means evil so
there was an evil demon and he wanted to
interrupt the teaching so we caused a
rain of food like I don't know french
fries and then people in the audience
stopped listening and they started
catching the french fries then when they
got tired of that he started dropping
money in and they stopped listening to
over good time you know and then after a
while people started to listen again so
he emanate as a beautiful girl dancing
and talked a meadow katella then he
didn't like it he got irritated with the
demon he was an aria so he took a flower
garland and he put it over her head and
suddenly she looks very ugly you know
like a demon or something she's show her
true form and then everyone started
listening good one everyone started to
listen okay they're just showing the
power of even a Hinayana oh yeah
okay now you want to hear the real story
so it's in a future that Nick was
teaching in God
which is called yeah it's called the
future of wise and the force summer
Wiseman and summer foods but I need a
little scent it is a song okay it's
called the citrus typically points my
people
okay done whoo all right here it goes
with the good Peniche me double
debatable
he achieved now they make it clear he
achieved non returner non returner
which means almost our heart he doesn't
have to come back to the desire realm
Dana yeah shaky Candela Shannon I'm a
doctor you know from a young age he left
the homeless came back he can Jason de
película come due today and his parents
gave him to the monastery ginger papa he
started taking laments mouse ray de Melo
Nishizawa nos so on us when he reached
20 years old he was allowed to take vows
take monks you're not allowed to take 12
hours until you're 20
yeah but also he took four thousand
numbers okay so as I see liking him but
subatomic guitar and then after that he
became our heart okay resumed our
membership module content a he
understood the three knowledge is and
the six kinds of clairvoyance Marla
Pappas Amy Schaefer girth he became a
consummate teachers Dharma teacher named
Obama did that amateur and many
people would come to his teachings case
a dictation key karma burning two
circuits on say don't say charging the
puppy then this demon got irritated that
he was having such big classes and he
dropped money on the audience okay Jimmy
and umeå Chester and everyone stopped
listening and try to grab the money
okay dad you mean karma birthday the
next day he was teaching again children
botella he he was teaching good dicta
dito changi and then the demon dropped
flower violence in the from the sky
child pop a crude attempt to so everyone
got distracted by these beautiful
flowers dance a 1013 kilometer cheetah
matcha ballet next day he was teaching
again do Java Lama to turn pink on
cotton Connie that demon emanated as the
king of elephants in a dark blue color
okay tell a group with six tusks okay
Tara really ours Ingrid any he's is so
big that each talk has a lake on the end
of it okay
the lake a whole lake on the end of the
Tusk there's a whole garden in so huge
that there's a garden on the end of the
talk okay and the lake okay terrorizing
a super rating under method under each
leg has seven lotuses huge Lotus is
growing in it okay never let another
she'll keep him a building and each
Lotus has a woman made of crystal
dancing okay there's a one seven seven
crystal ladies dancing in each flower on
each lake on each task of this elephant
that's more destructive okay
promote they dock young so Sonia Roma
today each one was doing a
dans la botella called the donkey cart
and even the elephant was going like
this was good authority a little bit
then everybody just wants to watch the
elephant in the Bentley the very minimum
do day the next day he was teaching
again table a dirty government marching
some emotion sensation summers working
on the over to me and then then that
demon emanated one a single very
beautiful woman who walked through the
teaching and distracted everybody
especially the boys chicken though
course she can on the only to me makin
that they make me do bata make me Zumba
means they couldn't stop they couldn't
even blink
they're like that you know mean Tim
Burton Kenya but Jade oh they forgot to
listen to the Dharma
game but talk to then the Arya he went
like this or something and she changed
to her skeleton then everybody's like
ear then they start to think about death
and then they said please page please
pages are going in the story that's the
real story he showed their skeletons he
made her look at her skull and everybody
forgot how beautiful she was
okay alright